Portfolio Club Records
Portfolio Club Records
- 2000-2025
  - Our Supreme Court, 2009-2010; 5 folders (Box 19)
    Jan. 18 - The Dirty Dozen
    Feb. 1 - The Nine
    Feb. 15 - The 2000 Election
    Mar. 1 - The Oneida Indian Claim
    Mar. 15 - The Current Court
    Apr. 1 - Where Do We Go From Here?
    Apr. 19 - President's luncheon
  - Wonders of the World, 2010-2011; 6 folders (Box 20)
    President's notes (president Jean Graham died during her Portfolio Year; her notes are preserved here)
    Correspondence (see also President's notes, above)
    Oct. 4 - Pyramidal Wonders
    Oct. 18 - Circular Wonders
    Nov. 1 - Linear Wonders
    Nov. 15 - Monumental Wonders
    Dec. 6 - Statuary Wonders
    Dec. 20 - Sacred Wonders / Holiday celebration
    Jan. 17 - Residential Wonders
    Feb. 7 - Graphic Wonders
    Feb. 21 - Flowing Wonders
    Mar. 7 - Frozen Wonders
    Mar. 21 - Expansive Wonders
    Apr. 4 - Endangered Wonders
    Apr. 20 - President's luncheon
  - American Utopias, 2011-2012; 5 folders (Box 20)
    Oct. 3 - The Shakers
    Oct. 17 - The Harmony Society
    Nov. 7 - Nashoba
    Nov. 21 - Brook Farm
    Dec. 5 - The North American Phalanx
    Dec. 19 - Holiday celebration: Community
    Jan. 16 - The Oneida Community
    Feb. 6 - The Roycroft Community
    Feb. 20 - The Hutterites
    Mar. 5 - The Peace Mission Movement
    Mar. 19 - Twin Oaks Community
    Apr. 2 - Ecovillage at Ithaca
    Apr. 16 - President's luncheon
  - Symbolism, 2012-2013; 4 folders (Box 20)
    Papers:
    Oct 1 - Symbols in everyday life
    Oct 15 - Symbolism in our Capitol
    Nov 15 - Symbols of the dance
    Nov 19 - The Golden Ratio
    Dec 3 - Animal symbolism
    Dec 17 - Symbols of Christmas
    Jan 21 - Literary symbology
    Feb 4 - Symbolism of food
    Feb 18 - Color and art symbolism
    Mar 4 - Witchcraft
    Mar 18 - Lost symbols
    Apr 1 - Trademarks
    Apr 15 - President's luncheon
  - Exploring Poseidon's Realm, 2013-2014; 5 folders (Box 21)
    Historian's report and handouts
    Oct 7 - A miscellany of curiosities
    Oct 21 - Salt: The only rock we eat
    Nov 4 - Bon voyage!
    Nov 18 (Guest Day) - A mermaid's tears
    Dec 2 - Sailing under the black flag
    Dec 16 - holiday celebration
    Jan 20 - Seward's icebox is melting
    Feb 3 - Pillars of light
    Feb 17 - The power and glory of waves
    Mar 3 - Flotsam and jetsam
    Mar 17 - Delicacies of the sea
    Apr 7 - The empty ocean
    Apr 21 - President's luncheon
  - The Future of the 1980s, 2014-2015; 8 folders (Box 21)
    Historians
    Biographical research on early members (Ella Wyman Brewer, Ellen Fairchild)
    Constitution and bylaws, revised
    Oct 6 - Water, water everywhere
    Oct 20 - Chernobyl
    Nov 3 - Merry go round of marriage
    Nov 17 (Guest Day) - The Human Genome Project
    Dec 8 - Bhopal [Union Carbide disaster]
    Dec 15 - Holiday celebration
    Jan 19 - Give me some space [space program]
    Feb 2 - HIV/AIDS
    Feb 16 - Video Games
    Mar 2 - The day of five billion [overpopulation]
    Mar 16 - Protests
    Apr 6 - Millennials
    Apr - President's luncheon
  - Innovation, 2015-2016; 6 folders (Box 21)
    Biographical research on early members (Eloise Holden Nottingham; Sarah, Miriam and Alice Gardner)
    Oct 5 - Mining essential metals
    Oct 19 - The sublimity of color
    Nov 2 (Guest Day) - Nothing to wear?
    Dec 7 - Giving structures pizazz
    Dec 21 - Holiday celebration
    Jan 18 - Silicon
    Feb 16 - Put on your hard hats
    Mar 7 - Rubber
    Apr 4 - Replaceable you
    Apr 18 - President's luncheon
  - The Culture of Cuisine, 2016-2017; 7 folders (Box 22)
    Minutes and president's notes
    Historians' file
    Oct 13 - Food: Trajectory
    Oct 17 - China: A culinary cosmos
    Nov 7 - Rituals and traditions of food
    Dec 5 - Holiday celebration
    Jan 16 - Italian cuisine
    Feb 6 - Culture of cuisine in South America
    Feb 20 - Cuisine of Africa
    Mar 7 - Globalization and food
    Apr 3 - The culture of cuisine in France
    Apr 17 - President's luncheon
  - The Renaissance and its Echoes in the Modern World, 2017-2018; 6 folders (Box 22)
    Oct 2 - The prequel
    Oct 16 - Art and architecture
    Nov 6 - Politics and society
    Dec 4 - Religion
    Dec 18 - Holiday gathering
    Jan 15 - Literature
    Feb 8 - Women's work
    Mar 5 - Science, exploration and globalization
    Apr 2 - Echoes of the Renaissance
    Apr 16 - President's luncheon
    Miscellany - technology survey, information on early members Mrs A.F. (Annie Deming) Beard and Mrs. Frank (Helen Augusta Goodwin) Beard
- Memorabilia
  - Attendance log, 1968-1985 (Oversize 4)
  - Binder for minutes, one large, one small, both embossed with "Portfolio Club" in gold (Oversize 4)
  - Clipping, "The Families of Early Syracuse," about Mary Dana Hicks Prang (Oversize 1)
  - Clippings, 1899-2018 (gaps); undated; about the club and various members; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Collages from club's 125th anniversary luncheon, 2000 (Oversize 1)
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1939; 1956,; 1966-1967,; 1976,; 2000,; 2011 (Box 16)
  - Exhibit material, 2008; gathered or produced for the exhibit on the Portfolio Club; clippings, photographs, research material, etc. (Oversize 1)
  - Group photo of club members, 2008 (Oversize 1)
  - The Knickerbocker Children (Box 16)
  - Obituaries, memorial tributes (alphabetical), 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Photo-collage from annual meeting, 2006 (Oversize 3)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 16)
  - "Portfolio Club: A Goodly Heritage", 2000; originally written in 1975; includes updates from Mary Ten Eyck and Bette Maltby (Box 16)
  - "Portfolio Club: A Refuge of Friendship and Learning", Fall 1991; from the Syracuse University Courier, Vol. XXVI, No. 2 (Box 16)
  - Printing plates for earyl versions of booklet, individual small lead plates mounted on wood blocks; mostly simple designs (Box 23)
  - Proposal letters (alphabetical), letters written proposing prospective members (Box 16)
  - Resignation letters (alphabetical), letters resigning membership, or requesting change to Associate status (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook [1], 100th Anniversary, 1975 (Oversize 5)
  - Scrapbook [2], 100th Anniversary, 1975 (Oversize 6)
  - Scrapbook [3], clippings and photographs, no date given (Oversize 6)
  - "A Touch of Tiffany" by Dorothy K. White (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous, letterhead, Christmas songbooks, undated correspondence, succession lists, etc. (Box 16)